crystalcommerce.com 2016-12-04

# Privacy Policy - Crystal Commerce Crystal Commerce

At CrystalCommerce, we are strongly committed to customer privacy. This document outlines how we will collect and use your personal information. The policies below are applicable to data and information collected through the CrystalCommerce website and affiliated webistes (including crystalcommerce.com), the CrystalCommerce application, the affiliated network of websites (CrystalCommerce Intra-network), including any versions optimized for viewing on a wireless or tablet device; all email newsletters published or distributed by CrystalCommerce; all apps published by CrystalCommerce; and all other interactive features, sites, and communications provided by CrystalCommerce, including any information and data we receive from our CrystalCommerce Intra-network members (“Members”) who use our technology (collectively, “Sites”), however accessed and/or used, that are operated by CrystalCommerce, made available by CrystalCommerce, or produced and maintained by CrystalCommerce (collectively “CrystalCommerce” or “we”, “us”, or “our”). We have established this privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) to let you know the kinds of personal information we may gather during your visit to the Sites, why we gather your information, what we use your personal information for, when we might disclose your personal information, and how you can manage your personal information.

 **Please be advised that the practices described in this Privacy Policy apply only to information gathered online at the Sites. It does not apply to information that you may submit to us offline or to websites maintained by other companies or organizations to which we may link or who may link to us.**

 **By visiting these Sites, you are accepting the practices described in our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Sites. We reserve the right to modify or amend the terms of our Privacy Policy from time to time without notice. Your continued use of the Sites following the posting of changes to these terms will mean you accept those changes. If we intend to apply the modifications or amendments to this Privacy Policy retroactively or to personal information already in our possession, we will provide you with notice of the modifications or amendments.**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or don’t see your concerns addressed here, you should contact us by email at legal@crystalcommerce.com.

#### What Information About Me Is Collected and Stored?

We collect two basic types of information from you in conjunction with your use of the Sites, personal information and non-personal information. Personal information is information that you may supply to us, as described more fully below, e.g., when you place an order, complete a survey, register on a Site, upload content, participate in a community, or provide your e-mail address. Personal information is any information that can individually identify you and includes, among other things, your name, e-mail address, telephone number, postal address, credit card, billing and contact information. Non-personal information includes information that does not personally identify you, but it may include tracking and usage information about your location, demographics, use of the Sites and the Internet.

#### Personal Information

As a general matter, you can browse the Sites without submitting your personal information to us. However, there are a number of circumstances in which you may supply us with your personal information. The following lists the most common ways in which we may collect your personal information:

    * Registration for an account on the Sites;
    * Profile information that you provide for your user profile;
    * Sign up to receive alerts or other information via email, text or instant message from CrystalCommerce;
    * Request for customer service or other assistance;
    * Site-related communications, e.g. account verification, technical notification
    * Participation in communities, chat rooms and comment threads, and other interactive Sites;
    * Purchasing products and providing related billing information;
    * Submission of content or other data and information on any part of the Sites that permits it; and/or
    * Any other place on the Sites where you knowingly volunteer personal information.

#### Non-Personal Information

In addition, when you interact with the Sites, we may collect certain information that does not identify you individually and our servers may automatically keep an activity log of your use of our Sites (“Non-Personal Information”). Generally, we collect and store the following categories of Non-Personal Information:

    * Non-identifiable demographic data such as age, gender, and five digit zip code as part of collecting personal information;
    * Device information about your computer, mobile device, or other device that you use to access the Sites. This information may include IP address, geolocation information, unique device identifiers, browser type, browser language, and other transactional information
    * Analytics and usage information about your use of the Sites;
    * Additional “traffic data” and log files such as time of access, date of access, software crash reports, session identification number, access times, and referring website addresses;
    * Store, inventory, product, and pricing information if you are a retailer or seller;
    * Other information regarding your use of the Sites, including your purchase history, wish-listed items, and sale history.

#### Collection of Your Source IP Address/Location Information

We collect and store location information about you on the Sites and associated with your account that you volunteer on the Sites or enable through the Sites or your device. We will collect location information to help improve the services for you. We also collect and store your device’s source IP address which may disclose the location of your device at the time you access the Sites. Advertisements and certain content may be directed to you as a result of this data. In addition, in some cases the Sites can deliver content based on your current location if you choose to enable that feature. If you enable that feature, your current location will be stored locally on your device which will be used by the Sites to serve you certain content tied to your location. If you elect to have your location-based searches saved to your history, we will store such information on our servers.

#### Collection of Personal and Non-Personal Information From Other Sources

We also may collect and store information about you that we receive from other sources (including by us from our offline interactions with you) to, among other things, enable us to update and correct the information contained in our database and to better customize your experience on the Sites.

#### Collection of Personal Information From or Through Social Media Sites

When you interact with any CrystalCommerce page or account on a social media platform, such as Facebook, Twitter, Google+, Tumblr, LinkedIn, YouTube, or Pinterest, we may collect the personal information that you make available to us on that page or account including your account ID or “handle.” However, we will comply with the privacy policies of the corresponding social media platform and we will only collect and store such personal information that we are permitted to collect by these social media platforms.

#### Use of Cookies, Flash Cookies, Web Storage, and Web Beacons

Like many websites, we use “cookies”, which are small text files that are stored on your computer or equipment when you visit certain online pages that record your preferences and actions. We use cookies to track use of the Sites and online services. We may also use cookies to monitor traffic, improve the Sites and make them easier to use and/or more relevant for your use. You may occasionally get cookies from companies advertising on our behalf. We do not control these cookies, and these cookies are not subject to this cookie policy.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but, if you prefer, you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies. If you delete your cookies or if you set your web browser to decline cookies, some features of the Sites may not work or may not work as designed. For more information on cookies and how to disable them, you can consult the information provided by the Interactive Advertising Bureau at www.allaboutcookies.org.

We may also use web beacons or flash cookies. A web beacon or flash cookie (also known as “action tags,” “tracer tags,” or “single-pixel gifs”) is an invisible graphic on a web page that is programmed to collect non-personal information about your use of a given website. We do not share or provide Personal Information we may collect through such web beacons, such as names, e-mail addresses and phone numbers without your express permission.

We may also use “Web Storage” to store data about your use of the Sites. Web Storage is a feature in some browsers that permits websites to store data within your browser rather than within a cookie. This should make this data more secure and make your browser perform better. We do not share or provide Personal Information we may store in Web Storage, such as names, e-mail addresses and phone numbers without your express permission.

We work with third-party advertising companies who may utilize flash or enhanced cookies or web beacons to better provide advertisements about goods and services that may be of interest to you. These partners do not have access to or use your name, address, e-mail address, telephone number or other personal information from us. They may, however, anonymously track your Internet usage across other websites in their networks beyond these Sites. To learn more about the use of this information or to choose not to have this information used by our third-party advertising partners by opting out please visit the Network Advertising Initiative by clicking http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp.

#### Is Personal Information Collected from Children?

Unless otherwise disclosed during collection and subject to parent or guardian consent, CrystalCommerce does not knowingly collect personal identifiable information from children under 13 years of age. If you are under 13 years of age you should not provide personally identifiable information to CrystalCommerce without providing us with consent from your parents. If CrystalCommerce discovers that a child under the age of 13 has provided CrystalCommerce with personally identifiable information and we do not have parental consent, CrystalCommerce will immediately delete that child’s information from the Sites.

#### How Do We Use Your Information?

We use the information we learn from you to help us personalize and continually improve your experience on the Sites. We may use your Personal and Non-Personal Information in the following ways:

##### General Uses

    * Provide you with the content, products and Sites you request.
    * Allow you to create accounts and sign-in to our services.
    * Upload your content to the Sites as you request.
    * Communicate with you about your account or transactions with us and send you information about features and enhancements on the Sites.
    * Communicate with you about changes to our policies.
    * Communicate with you about your comment to a community.
    * Personalize content and experiences on the Sites, including providing you reports, recommendations, offers and feedback based on your preferences or products that you own.
    * Optimize or improve our products, Sites and operations.
    * Automatically update the Sites on your device.
    * Detect, investigate, and prevent activities that may violate our policies or be illegal.
    * Perform statistical, demographic, and marketing analyses of users of the Sites.

#### Combination of Your Personal Information

We use the information from one portion of the Sites on other portions of Sites or in our network of Sites, all of which are owned and operated by CrystalCommerce or our Members, and we may combine information gathered from multiple portions of the Sites (and multiple of our Members’ websites) into a single customer record. We also use and/or combine information that we collect offline or we collect or receive from third party sources to enhance, expand, and check the accuracy of your customer records.

#### Use of Your Location Information

Specifically, we use your location information to:

    * Provide you with the products and Sites you request;
    * Personalize content on the Sites, including providing you reports, recommendations and feedback based on your preferences;
    * Optimize or improve our products, operations and the Sites;
    * Detect, investigate, and prevent activities that may violate our policies or be illegal; and/or
    * Perform statistical, demographic, and marketing analyses of users of the Sites and their purchasing patterns.

#### Who Do We Provide Your Personal Information To?

Except as disclosed in this Privacy Policy, we do not disclose information about your Personal Information collected online to any companies not part of CrystalCommerce or its subsidiaries or related entities or the CrystalCommerce Intra-network. In no event will we sell or rent your Personal Information as part of a customer list or similar transaction.

#### Business Partners and Third Parties

We share Personal Information only to the extent of what is needed by our business partners and third parties to allow the Sites to function. We may also share your Personal Information with third parties that provide products and services that we think you may be interested in. Although our treatment of your Personal Information is governed by this Privacy Policy, the business partner or third party’s treatment of your Personal Information will be governed by the business partner or third party’s privacy policy. You may withdraw your consent to our sharing of your Personal Information with business partners and third parties at any time by following the opt-out process described below.

#### Third-Party Agents

We have third party agents, subsidiaries, affiliates and partners that perform functions on our behalf, such as hosting, billing, push notifications, storage, bandwidth, content management tools, analytics, customer sites, fraud protection, etc. These entities have access to the Personal Information needed to perform their functions and are contractually obligated to maintain the confidentiality and security of that Personal Information.

#### Emergency Situations

We may also use or disclose Personal Information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to (a) conform to applicable law or comply with legal process served on us or the Sites; (b) protect and defend our rights or property, the Sites or our users, and (c) act under emergency circumstances to protect the personal safety of us, our affiliates, agents, or the users of the Sites or the public.

#### Use of Non-Personal Information

We may disclose or share Non-Personal Information (or other information, other than Personal Information) in any other manner that we deem appropriate or necessary. Among other things, we will disclose Non-Personal Information to third parties to help us determine how people use parts of the Sites and who our users are so we and our Members can improve the Sites. We will also disclose Non-Personal Information to our partners and other third parties about how our users collectively use the Sites.

#### CrystalCommerce E-mail and Text Communications

E-mail communications and text messages sent from us or through us are designed to make your CrystalCommerce experience more efficient. By participating in the Sites, you specifically agree to accept and consent to receiving e-mail communications and text messages initiated from us or through us, which include, without limitation: message notification e-mails, e-mails or text messages informing you about potential services and promotions. We send emails informing you of new and existing features we provide. Standard text messaging charges applied by your cell phone carrier will apply to text messages we send. If you change your mobile phone provider, the notification Sites may be deactivated for your phone number and you may need to re-enroll in the notification Sites. CrystalCommerce reserves the right to cancel the notification Sites at any time. If you do not wish to receive any of our e-mail communications or text messages, please do not use the Sites.

#### What Steps Are Taken To Keep Personal Information Secure?

We are concerned about ensuring the security of your Personal Information. We exercise great care in providing secure transmission of your information from your device to our servers. Personal Information collected by the Sites is stored in secure server environments that are not accessible by the public. Our security procedures mean that we may occasionally request proof of identity before we disclose your Personal Information to you. Please understand, however, that while we try our best to safeguard your Personal Information once we receive it, no transmission of data over the Internet or any other public network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.

#### How Can We Transfer Your Personal Information?

Your information collected through the Sites may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which CrystalCommerce, its clients, affiliates or Sites providers maintain facilities. CrystalCommerce, its clients, affiliates, or Site providers may transfer information that we collect about you, including personal information across borders and from your country or jurisdiction to other countries or jurisdictions around the world. If you are located in the United States or other regions with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from US law, please note that we may transfer information, including personal information, to a country and jurisdiction that does not have the same data protection laws as your jurisdiction. By registering for and using the Sites you consent to the transfer of information to the US or to any other country in which CrystalCommerce, its clients, affiliates or Sites providers maintain facilities and the use and disclosure of information about you as described in this Privacy Policy.

#### How Long Do We Keep Your Information?

Following termination or deactivation of your account, CrystalCommerce, its clients, affiliates, or its Sites providers may retain information (including your profile information) and user content for a commercially reasonable time for backup, archival, and/or audit purposes. If you have any questions about termination or deactivation of your account, please contact us directly at legal@crystalcommerce.com

#### Your Obligations to Keep Your Access Rights Secure

You promise to: (a) provide true, accurate, current and complete information about yourself and your business as prompted by a Site’s registration form (“Registration Data”); and (b) maintain and promptly update the Registration Data to keep it true, accurate, current and complete. If you provide any information that is untrue, inaccurate, not current or incomplete, or CrystalCommerce has reasonable grounds to suspect that such information is untrue, inaccurate, not current or incomplete, CrystalCommerce has the right to suspend or terminate your account and refuse any and all current or future use of the Sites (or any portion thereof). You are entirely responsible for the security and confidentiality of your password and account. Furthermore, you are entirely responsible for any and all activities that occur under your account.

#### What Happens When I Link To or From Another Website?

The Sites may contain links to other websites operated by affiliates of CrystalCommerce, Members, or third parties. Please be advised that the practices described in this Privacy Policy do not apply to information gathered through these other websites. We are not responsible for the actions and privacy policies of third parties and other websites.

#### What About Contests, Sweepstakes or Games?

When we run a contest or sweepstakes or game relating to the Sites, it will be accompanied by a set of rules. The rules for each contest, sweepstakes or game will specify how the information gathered from you for entry will be used and disclosed if it is different than as described in this Privacy Policy. In conjunction with your entry in such contest or sweepstakes, Personal Information will be collected only if you voluntarily submit it to us.

#### Public Areas, Chat Rooms, Reviews, and Community Areas

Please remember that any information you share in public areas, such as message boards/forums, social media or feedback sections, becomes public and anyone may take and use that information. Please be careful about what you disclose and do not post any Personal Information that you expect to keep private. Please consult the applicable guidelines, if any, for use of our chat rooms and other community areas for more information.

#### Governing Law

The Sites are published in the United States. We attempt to protect the Personal Information of all users of the Sites and we attempt to comply with local data protection and consumer rights laws to the extent they may apply to the CrystalCommerce Sites. If you are uncertain whether this Privacy Policy conflicts with the applicable local privacy laws where you are located, you should not submit your Personal Information to CrystalCommerce.

#### Notice to Non-US Users

If you are located outside the United States of America, you should be aware that your personally identifiable information will be transferred to the United States of America, the laws of which may be deemed by your country to have inadequate data protection. If you are located in a country outside the United States of America and voluntarily submit personal information to us, you thereby consent to the general use of such information as provided in this privacy policy and to the transfer of that information to, and/or storage of that information in, the United States of America or any other country in which a CrystalCommerce Intra-network Member’s site is hosted. You appoint CrystalCommerce to perform any such transfer of such information to any such country and to store and process your information in order to provide you services related to the Sites.

#### Changes to This Policy

Over time, CrystalCommerce may add new services and features to the Sites. In the event that these additions affect our Privacy Policy, this document will be updated appropriately. We will post this document and updated versions prominently so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information and whether we will disclose it to anyone. We do, however, recommend that you read this Privacy Policy each time you use the Sites in case you missed our notice of changes to the Privacy Policy. We will not, however, materially change our policies and practices to make them less protective of Personal Information we have previously collected from you without your express consent.

#### How Do I Opt-Out or Correct Information About Me?

You may always opt-out of receiving future commercial e-mail messages and newsletters from CrystalCommerce. We provide you with the opportunity to opt-out of receiving commercial communications from us by going into your profile settings and choosing the appropriate options. To opt-out, you can also send us a message at legal@crystalcommerce.com.

#### Your California Privacy Rights

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits customers of CrystalCommerce who are California residents to request certain information regarding its disclosure of their personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an e-mail to us at legal@crystalcommerce.com. These Sites will respect your browser’s Do Not Track signals (or other well-established, commercially available mechanisms that provide you with the ability to exercise choice regarding the collection of Personal Information). If we receive a Do Not Track notice, we will stop using any Personal Information for online behavioral advertising purposes.
